The NFL Draft is just over a week away
and Wednesday we will get a sneak peek
at how the Ravens brass view this draft
class. General Manager Eric DeCosta and
Jesse Minter will address the media to
preview their strategy. Starting with
pick number 14, DeCosta will have 11
picks at his disposal barring any
trades. Now often called the liars
luncheon by media as DeCosta plays his
cards close to his vest [music] a week
out from the draft lest another team get
wind of who the Ravens favor. It will be
DeCosta's first draft building a roster
for new head coach Jesse Minter. But
DeCosta said at the combine he doesn't
anticipate that changing who the Ravens
draft as they stick to their best player
available mantra. Minter will be
building his own version of the Ravens
defense and talked at the combine about
how he evaluates talent especially at
the pass rush position. Number one
production and I think there's a size
speed length element we're kind of a
requirement. Uh there may be guys that
maybe are an inch or two shorter but
then they bring something else
really above the level um and so there's
a there's a really wide variety of guys
this year that have been really
productive. Some that are third and
fourth year, some that are fifth and
sixth year the way the way college works
now so
uh I feel like there'll be a lot of guys
in the draft that that could potentially
help in that regard. Minter added that
his collaboration will be very similar
with DeCosta to the previous regime
something he was familiar with in LA
with the Chargers. The coaching staff
will do deep dives on their respective
positions and provide input. Wednesday
DeCosta will share insight into what he
believes the strength of this draft
class are as his staff has dug into all
the prospects. DeCosta made 11 picks
last year as well and he values the
influx of young talent that that brings
as Minter's new staff will then be
tasked to develop them. At last year's
pre-draft presser he identified the 2025
class as one that had a chance to be
really good for the Ravens also in the
post-draft undrafted free agency phase.
Something that proved to be very true
when three undrafted rookies made that
initial 53-man roster last August. So
stay tuned for any gems like that in
this week's presser but you may have to
listen carefully to pick up on them.
That press conference will be
live-streamed on our Facebook page,
YouTube channel, app and website
Wednesday at 12:15 p.m. Thanks for
watching. We'll be back with you
tomorrow.